[
    {
        "question": "Which American singer, songwriter and dancer released the album 'Bad'?",
        "answer": "Michael Jackson",
        "options": [
            "Michael Jackson",
            "Nicki Minaj",
            "Neil Young",
            "Eric Clapton"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which religious sect living primarily in Ohio and southeast Pennsylvania gets its name from a 17th century Swiss Mennonite bishop?",
        "answer": "The Amish",
        "options": [
            "The Amish",
            "The Shakers",
            "The Hutterites",
            "The Mennonites"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Molinology the study of?",
        "answer": "Windmills and similar devices",
        "options": [
            "Windmills and similar devices",
            "Plant communities",
            "Massage",
            "The earth's atmosphere"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Dili is the capital city of which country?",
        "answer": "Timor-Leste",
        "options": [
            "Timor-Leste",
            "Grenada",
            "Kuwait",
            "Romania"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is a traditional Mexican sport?",
        "answer": "Charreada",
        "options": [
            "Charreada",
            "Bandy",
            "Korfball",
            "Futsal"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the term for a person who gets sexual pleasure from watching others in the act?",
        "answer": "Voyeur",
        "options": [
            "Voyeur",
            "Tinker",
            "Stalker",
            "Spy"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the word for a group of elk?",
        "answer": "A gang",
        "options": [
            "A gang",
            "A watch",
            "A muster",
            "A bevy"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which piece of written work starts with the line 'Mr Utterson the lawyer was a man of a rugged countenance, that was never lighted by a smile; cold, scanty and embarrassed in discourse; backward in sentiment; lean, long, dusty, dreary and yet somehow lovable.'?",
        "answer": "Strange Case of Dr Jekyll and Mr Hyde",
        "options": [
            "Strange Case of Dr Jekyll and Mr Hyde",
            "The City & the City",
            "Frankenstein",
            "The Hunchback of Notre Dame"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which car manufacturer makes the Astra?",
        "answer": "Opel",
        "options": [
            "Opel",
            "Honda",
            "Ferrari",
            "Rolls-Royce"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these cities is in Denmark?",
        "answer": "Odense",
        "options": [
            "Odense",
            "Barcelona",
            "Oslo",
            "Helsinki"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which author wrote 'The Nightingale'?",
        "answer": "Hans Christian Andersen",
        "options": [
            "Hans Christian Andersen",
            "Beatrix Potter",
            "Søren Kierkegaard",
            "Oscar Wilde"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Ancient Greek creature had snakes for hair?",
        "answer": "Medusa",
        "options": [
            "Medusa",
            "Minotaur",
            "Harpy",
            "Siren"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Where Are The Atlas Mountains?",
        "answer": "North Africa",
        "options": [
            "North Africa",
            "Australia",
            "Central America",
            "Eastern Europe"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which piece of written work starts with the line 'Someone must have been telling lies about Joseph K., for without having done anything wrong he was arrested one fine morning.'?",
        "answer": "The Trial",
        "options": [
            "The Trial",
            "Gulliver's Travels",
            "Carmen",
            "I Am Legend"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which actor has starred in films including Inception and The Revenant?",
        "answer": "Leonardo DiCaprio",
        "options": [
            "Leonardo DiCaprio",
            "Ralph Fiennes",
            "Brian Cox",
            "Kiefer Sutherland"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which author wrote 'Inferno'?",
        "answer": "Dan Brown",
        "options": [
            "Dan Brown",
            "Stephen King",
            "Donna Leon",
            "Frederik Pohl"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was Odysseus' son, who grew to manhood in his absence?",
        "answer": "Telemachus",
        "options": [
            "Telemachus",
            "Perseus",
            "Archimedes",
            "Icarus"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which region of the world uses '.sz' at the end of its web addresses?",
        "answer": "Eswatini",
        "options": [
            "Eswatini",
            "Switzerland",
            "South Korea",
            "Zambia"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "With which sport is Hicham El Guerrouj associated?",
        "answer": "Athletics",
        "options": [
            "Athletics",
            "Rugby Union",
            "Ice Hockey",
            "Cycling"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Tirana is the capital city of which country?",
        "answer": "Albania",
        "options": [
            "Albania",
            "Algeria",
            "Cameroon",
            "Belgium"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Port Moresby is the capital city of which country?",
        "answer": "Papua New Guinea",
        "options": [
            "Papua New Guinea",
            "Solomon Islands",
            "Namibia",
            "Sao Tome and Principe"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which technology was first developed for the U.S. military and is now used for navigation?",
        "answer": "GPS",
        "options": [
            "GPS",
            "BPS",
            "LPS",
            "TPS"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What do people mean when typing the letters 'POV' in a message on the internet?",
        "answer": "Point of View",
        "options": [
            "Point of View",
            "Plants or Vegetation",
            "Perform on Video",
            "Play on Vine"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which American rock band has hits including 'My Pal Foot Foot' and 'Gimmie Dat Ding'",
        "answer": "The Shaggs",
        "options": [
            "The Shaggs",
            "Guns N Roses",
            "Nirvana",
            "The Kingsmen"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the nickname of President Duvalier of Haiti, who died in 1971?",
        "answer": "Papa Doc",
        "options": [
            "Papa Doc",
            "Big Daddy",
            "Pa Lordy",
            "Man Man Judge"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Where in the world are muskmelons originally from?",
        "answer": "India",
        "options": [
            "India",
            "China",
            "Southeast Asia",
            "North America"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which actress has played roles in films including Pirates of the Caribbean: On Stranger Tides and Volver?",
        "answer": "Penélope Cruz",
        "options": [
            "Penélope Cruz",
            "Amy Adams",
            "Uma Thurman",
            "Cameron Diaz"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these cities is in Cuba?",
        "answer": "Havana",
        "options": [
            "Havana",
            "San Salvador",
            "Santiago",
            "Guatemala City"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these Russian cities is located on the Black Sea?",
        "answer": "Sochi",
        "options": [
            "Sochi",
            "Moscow",
            "Saint Petersburg",
            "Kazan"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which actress has starred in films including Gravity and Crash?",
        "answer": "Sandra Bullock",
        "options": [
            "Sandra Bullock",
            "Charlize Theron",
            "Emma Thompson",
            "Maggie Smith"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the NBC drama series set in County General Hospital?",
        "answer": "ER",
        "options": [
            "ER",
            "Grey's Anatomy",
            "House M.D.",
            "Chicago Med"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the sitcom that introduced the holiday tradition of \"Festivus\"?",
        "answer": "Seinfeld",
        "options": [
            "Seinfeld",
            "Friends",
            "The Big Bang Theory",
            "The Simpsons"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Who Composed \"The Planets\" Suite?",
        "answer": "Gustav Holst",
        "options": [
            "Gustav Holst",
            "Edward Elgar",
            "Igor Stravinsky",
            "Claude Debussy"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which book contains the character 'Hazel Motes'?",
        "answer": "Wise Blood",
        "options": [
            "Wise Blood",
            "Tinker",
            "On the Road",
            "Portnoy's Complaint"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which author wrote 'Norwegian Wood'?",
        "answer": "Haruki Murakami",
        "options": [
            "Haruki Murakami",
            "Oscar Wilde",
            "Umberto Eco",
            "Søren Kierkegaard"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which song begins with the lyrics: \"I wanna be the very best...\"?",
        "answer": "\"Pokémon Theme\" by Jason Paige",
        "options": [
            "\"Pokémon Theme\" by Jason Paige",
            "\"Let it Be\" by the Beatles",
            "\"I'm Real (Murder Remix) by Jennifer Lopez and Ja Rule",
            "\"In da Club\" by 50 Cent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Nairobi is the capital city of which country?",
        "answer": "Kenya",
        "options": [
            "Kenya",
            "Colombia",
            "Georgia",
            "Uzbekistan"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country would you find Schönbrunn Palace and Gardens?",
        "answer": "Austria",
        "options": [
            "Austria",
            "Jordan",
            "Bulgaria",
            "Israel"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "___________ is the only country in the Middle East that does not have a desert.",
        "answer": "Lebanon",
        "options": [
            "Lebanon",
            "Jordan",
            "Israel",
            "Cyprus"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these drinks would you associate with Thailand?",
        "answer": "Sang Som Rum",
        "options": [
            "Sang Som Rum",
            "Pitorro",
            "Tuba",
            "Port wine"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Who Released The 70's Album \"Electric Warrior\"?",
        "answer": "T. Rex",
        "options": [
            "T. Rex",
            "Queen",
            "Talking Heads",
            "Black Sabbath"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which actor has had roles in films including Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice and The Untouchables?",
        "answer": "Kevin Costner",
        "options": [
            "Kevin Costner",
            "Dwayne Johnson",
            "Shah Rukh Khan",
            "Gérard Depardieu"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which chemical has the atomic number one?",
        "answer": "Hydrogen",
        "options": [
            "Hydrogen",
            "Oxygen",
            "Helium",
            "Carbon"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which actor has featured in films including Alice in Wonderland and The Hobbit: The Desolation of Smaug?",
        "answer": "Stephen Fry",
        "options": [
            "Stephen Fry",
            "Michael Ironside",
            "Luke Evans",
            "Tom Waits"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state is directly west of Indiana?",
        "answer": "Illinois",
        "options": [
            "Illinois",
            "Iowa",
            "Nebraska",
            "Kansas"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Where would you find the city of Barcelona?",
        "answer": "Spain",
        "options": [
            "Spain",
            "Germany",
            "Belgium",
            "Norway"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What fabled city was German adventurer Philipp Von Hutten searching for when he explored South America in the 1540s?",
        "answer": "El Dorado",
        "options": [
            "El Dorado",
            "Atlantis",
            "Shangri-La",
            "Camelot"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which NHL team got its name from a Disney film?",
        "answer": "The Anaheim Ducks",
        "options": [
            "The Anaheim Ducks",
            "The Chicago Blackhawks",
            "The Pittsburgh Penguins",
            "The New York Rangers"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What process is used for making beer, wine and sourdough bread?",
        "answer": "Fermentation",
        "options": [
            "Fermentation",
            "Cartography",
            "Substitution",
            "Titration"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is a Japanese form of wrestling where two heavyweight wrestlers attempt to push each other out of a marked circle?",
        "answer": "Sumo",
        "options": [
            "Sumo",
            "Kendo",
            "Judo",
            "Karate"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is codicology the study of?",
        "answer": "The preparation of books and manuscripts",
        "options": [
            "The preparation of books and manuscripts",
            "Water",
            "The nature and origins of knowledge",
            "Microorganisms"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which imaginery line approximately follows the 180 degree meridian through the Pacific Ocean?",
        "answer": "International Date Line",
        "options": [
            "International Date Line",
            "The Equator",
            "The Prime Meridian",
            "The Blood Meridian"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Aladdin was released in which year?",
        "answer": "1992",
        "options": [
            "1992",
            "1988",
            "1996",
            "2000"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "In volume measurements, how many fluid ounces are there in a cup?",
        "answer": "8",
        "options": [
            "8",
            "4",
            "12",
            "16"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which 1776 American Affirmation Asserted The Basic Rights Of All?",
        "answer": "The Declaration Of Independence",
        "options": [
            "The Declaration Of Independence",
            "The Constitution",
            "The Emancipation Procalation",
            "The Liberty Decree"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Irish rock band released the song 'Walk On'?",
        "answer": "U2",
        "options": [
            "U2",
            "Public Image Ltd.",
            "The Script",
            "The Cure"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is a basketball team based in Oklahoma City?",
        "answer": "Oklahoma City Thunder",
        "options": [
            "Oklahoma City Thunder",
            "Oklahoma City Wizards",
            "Oklahoma City Tigers",
            "Oklahoma City FC"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What chemical has the formula CH4?",
        "answer": "Methane",
        "options": [
            "Methane",
            "Potassium nitrate",
            "Iron Oxide",
            "Calcium sulphate dihydrate"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Viking Chief, Banished From Iceland, Founded The Norse Colonies On Greenland?",
        "answer": "Erik The Red",
        "options": [
            "Erik The Red",
            "Ragnar Lothbrok",
            "Leif Erikson",
            "Beowulf"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is a baseball team based in Toronto?",
        "answer": "Toronto Blue Jays",
        "options": [
            "Toronto Blue Jays",
            "Toronto Pelicans",
            "Toronto Sporting",
            "Toronto Blues"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a female hippopotamus known as?",
        "answer": "A Cow",
        "options": [
            "A Cow",
            "A Soar",
            "A Worker",
            "A Hen"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which novel tells the story of Ishmael, who goes to work on a whaler after feeling 'a damp, drizzly November' in his soul?",
        "answer": "Moby Dick",
        "options": [
            "Moby Dick",
            "The Old Man and the Sea",
            "20,000 Leagues Under the Sea",
            "The Sea-Wolf"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "In business, what does the job title CFO typically stand for?",
        "answer": "Chief Financial Officer",
        "options": [
            "Chief Financial Officer",
            "Chief Founding Officer",
            "Chief Fortune Officer",
            "Chief Federal Officer"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which author wrote 'Metamorphoses'?",
        "answer": "Ovid",
        "options": [
            "Ovid",
            "Miguel de Cervantes",
            "Oscar Wilde",
            "Agatha Christie"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which author wrote 'The Brothers Karamazov'?",
        "answer": "Fyodor Dostoyevsky",
        "options": [
            "Fyodor Dostoyevsky",
            "Vladimir Nabokov",
            "Leo Tolstoy",
            "Mikhail Bulgakov"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "From what did Alexander the Great suffer?",
        "answer": "Epilepsy",
        "options": [
            "Epilepsy",
            "Hemophilia",
            "Asthma",
            "Narcolepsy"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What two biblical cities did God destroy with fire and brimstone?",
        "answer": "Sodom and Gomorrah",
        "options": [
            "Sodom and Gomorrah",
            "Jericho and Babylon",
            "Pain and Pity",
            "Avarice and Jealousy"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the Linux operating system named after?",
        "answer": "Linus Torvalds",
        "options": [
            "Linus Torvalds",
            "Lin Wux",
            "Lionel Uxworth",
            "Linda Uxbridge"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Large Rodent Is Also Known As Nutria?",
        "answer": "Coypu",
        "options": [
            "Coypu",
            "Beaver",
            "Rat",
            "Capybara"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which author wrote 'Dekameron'?",
        "answer": "Giovanni Boccaccio",
        "options": [
            "Giovanni Boccaccio",
            "Dante Alighieri",
            "Agatha Christie",
            "Stephenie Meyer"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Christmas carol 'Away in a Manger', what was the little Lord Jesus asleep on?",
        "answer": "The Hay",
        "options": [
            "The Hay",
            "The Manger",
            "A Donkey",
            "The Stars"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "From which part of the world do potatoes originate?",
        "answer": "South America",
        "options": [
            "South America",
            "Africa",
            "Central Asia",
            "India"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What dog is named after a Mexican state?",
        "answer": "Chihuahua",
        "options": [
            "Chihuahua",
            "Maltese",
            "Pomeranian",
            "Havanese"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Chinese action star has broken a number of bones doing stunts and acted in films like 'Drunken Master' and 'Rumble in the Bronx'?",
        "answer": "Jackie Chan",
        "options": [
            "Jackie Chan",
            "Jet Li",
            "Bruce Lee",
            "Donnie Yen"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The Corsa is a model of car made by which manufacturer?",
        "answer": "Opel",
        "options": [
            "Opel",
            "Honda",
            "Ford",
            "Rolls-Royce"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the word for a group of ducks?",
        "answer": "A paddling",
        "options": [
            "A paddling",
            "A pack",
            "A muster",
            "A cete"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "With what sport is Jack Nicklaus associated?",
        "answer": "Golf",
        "options": [
            "Golf",
            "Tennis",
            "Cricket",
            "Rugby"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What would you call a male squirrel?",
        "answer": "A Buck",
        "options": [
            "A Buck",
            "A Bull",
            "A Hob",
            "A Ram"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is enigmatology the study of?",
        "answer": "Puzzles",
        "options": [
            "Puzzles",
            "Disease classification",
            "Life in outer space",
            "World War II"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which author wrote 'The Famous Five'?",
        "answer": "Enid Blyton",
        "options": [
            "Enid Blyton",
            "J. R. R. Tolkien",
            "Lewis Carroll",
            "Oscar Wilde"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the chemical formula for sodium bicarbonate?",
        "answer": "NaHCO3",
        "options": [
            "NaHCO3",
            "NaOCI",
            "Hg",
            "KNO3"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the national animal of Scotland?",
        "answer": "Unicorn",
        "options": [
            "Unicorn",
            "Lion",
            "Dragon",
            "Horse"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following describes Jean-Jacques Rousseau?",
        "answer": "Philosopher, author of Social Contract",
        "options": [
            "Philosopher, author of Social Contract",
            "Philosopher and mathematician who famously said \"I think, therefore I am.\"",
            "Greek philosopher and polymath",
            "French military leader who conquered much of Western Europe."
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What animal's meat can a Hindu not eat?",
        "answer": "Cow",
        "options": [
            "Cow",
            "Pig",
            "Sheep",
            "Goat"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a character in Shakespeare's play 'Hamlet'?",
        "answer": "Juliet",
        "options": [
            "Juliet",
            "Hamlet",
            "Ophelia",
            "Polonius"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Shawarma is a dish that is most associated with which part of the world?",
        "answer": "The Middle East",
        "options": [
            "The Middle East",
            "China",
            "Cameroon",
            "Guyana"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Who wrote the \"Discworld\" series?",
        "answer": "Terry Pratchett",
        "options": [
            "Terry Pratchett",
            "George R R Martin",
            "Ursula Le Guin",
            "Stephen King"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which English rock band released the studio album 'Yellow Submarine'?",
        "answer": "The Beatles",
        "options": [
            "The Beatles",
            "Deep Purple",
            "Feeder",
            "Uriah Heep"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What two US states are rectangular?",
        "answer": "Colorado and Wyoming",
        "options": [
            "Colorado and Wyoming",
            "Texas and Illinois",
            "Florida and Georgia",
            "Maine and Nevada"
        ]
    }
] 